Guide to the George Ellery Hale Papers HaleGE
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
- Family Correspondence, 1886–1944; 3; 2 linear feet (Tape HaleGE_01, Carton 2, Reel 68–71, Carton 4)
  - George Ellery Hale to Evelina Hale, 1926–1928; HaleGE_03_00_081_02; 138 pages (Box 81, Folder 2)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 69, frames 349 to 487.
  - George Ellery Hale to Evelina Hale, 1930; HaleGE_03_00_081_03; 35 pages (Box 81, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 69, frames 488 to 523.
  - George Ellery Hale to Evelina Hale, 1932–1934; HaleGE_03_00_081_04; 103 pages (Box 81, Folder 4)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 69, frames 524 to 627.
  - George Ellery Hale to Evelina Hale, undated; HaleGE_03_00_081_05; 9 pages (Box 81, Folder 5)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 69, frames 628 to 637.
  - Miscellaneous letters to Evelina Hale, 1912–1944; HaleGE_03_00_082_01; 45 pages (Box 82, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 69, frames 638 to 684.
  - Miscellaneous letters to Margaret Scherer, 1897–1914; HaleGE_03_00_082_02; 16 pages (Box 82, Folder 2)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 70, frames 20 to 36.
  - Margaret Scherer to George Ellery Hale, undated; HaleGE_03_00_082_03; 4 pages (Box 82, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 70, frames 37 to 41.
  - George Ellery Hale to Margaret Scherer, 1910–1936; HaleGE_03_00_082_04; 770 pages (Box 82, Folder 4)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 70, frames 42 to 812.
  - Miscellaneous family letters, 1886–1931; HaleGE_03_00_082_05; 383 pages (Box 82, Folder 5)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 70, frames 813 to 1197.
  - Evelina Hale to Margaret Scherer, 1906–1936; HaleGE_03_00_083_01; 991 pages (Box 83, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 71, frames 20 to 1012.
  - George Ellery Hale to mother, father, and sister, 1896–1897; HaleGE_03_00_083_02; 45 pages (Box 83, Folder 2)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 71, frames 1013 to 1057.
  - W. E. Hale, Aunt Martha, and Eunice Hale to Margaret and Paul Scherer, 1921–1937; HaleGE_03_00_083_03; 46 pages (Box 83, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 71, frames 1058 to 1105.
  - Evelina Hale to Miss Gianetti, 1936; HaleGE_03_00_083_04; 22 pages (Box 83, Folder 4)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 71, frames 1106 to 1128.
  - Miscellaneous, 1916–1938; HaleGE_03_00_083_05; 157 pages (Box 83, Folder 5)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 71, frames 1129 to 1288.
- Scientific Research, 1892–1936; 4; 3 linear feet (Tape HaleGE_02, Carton 2, Reel 72–73, Carton 4)
  Some scientific notebooks containing unidentifiable data tables, computations, and the like have been omitted from filming and digitization; the majority of these unfilmed notebooks contain mostly blank pages. The pagination of the filmed and digitized notebooks is discontinuous, since blank pages were not photographed.
  The documents relating to Hale's scientific work are of two types, notebooks and letters. There are twelve notebooks. Three appear to be for 1892, 1893, and 1909 respectively; the rest are dated 1905, 1906, 1911, 1916, 1917, 1920-1930, 1924, 1933, and 1934. In addition to strictly scientific work, Hale recorded in these notebooks ideas and plans for institutions with which he was associated, drafts of articles, and, on occasion, his general thoughts. The letters, all of which date between 1926 and 1936, deal with Hale's work on the spectrohelioscope.
  - Kenwood notebook, 1892; HaleGE_04_00_084_01 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Kenwood notebook, 1892; HaleGE_04_00_084_02 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Kenwood notebook, 1892; HaleGE_04_00_084_03; 22 pages (Box 84, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 20 to 44.
  - Kenwood notebook, 1893; HaleGE_04_00_084_04; 54 pages (Box 84, Folder 4)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 45 to 100.
  - Measurement of solar plates notebook 1, 1893; HaleGE_04_00_084_05 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Measurement of solar plates notebook 2, 1893; HaleGE_04_00_084_06 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Measurement of solar plates notebook 3, 1893; HaleGE_04_00_085_01 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Zeeman Effect notebook, 1898–1928; HaleGE_04_00_085_02 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Spectroscopy notebook, 1900; HaleGE_04_00_085_03 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Photographs for exhibit, 1904; HaleGE_04_00_085_04 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Solar Observatory memoranda notebook, 1905; HaleGE_04_00_085_05; 17 pages (Box 85, Folder 5)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 101 to 119.
  - Spot spectra, 1905; HaleGE_04_00_085_06 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Notes for articles, 1906–1908; HaleGE_04_00_085_07; 10 pages (Box 85, Folder 7)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 120 to 130.
  - Notebook, 1911; HaleGE_04_00_086_01; 51 pages (Box 86, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 131 to 182.
  - Rough notes, 1916; HaleGE_04_00_086_02 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, 1916; HaleGE_04_00_086_03; 84 pages (Box 86, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 183 to 267.
  - Notebook, 1917; HaleGE_04_00_086_04; 28 pages (Box 86, Folder 4)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 268 to 288.
  - Notebook, 1920–1930; HaleGE_04_00_086_05; 56 pages (Box 86, Folder 5)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 289 to 343.
  - Notebook, 1924; HaleGE_04_00_086_06; 13 pages (Box 86, Folder 6)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 344 to 358.
  - Notebook, 1934; HaleGE_04_00_087_01; 50 pages (Box 87, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 359 to 407.
  - Notebook, 1933; HaleGE_04_00_087_02 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, 1933; HaleGE_04_00_087_03; 50 pages (Box 87, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 408 to 450.
  - Notebook, 1894–1899; HaleGE_04_00_088_01 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, undated; HaleGE_04_00_088_02 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, 1933; HaleGE_04_00_088_03 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, 1933; HaleGE_04_00_088_04 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, 1933; HaleGE_04_00_088_05 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, 1933; HaleGE_04_00_088_06 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, 1909; HaleGE_04_00_088_07; 102 pages (Box 88, Folder 7)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 72, frames 451 to 562.
  - Notebook, undated; HaleGE_04_00_089_01 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, undated; HaleGE_04_00_089_02 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, undated; HaleGE_04_00_089_03 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, undated; HaleGE_04_00_089_04 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, undated; HaleGE_04_00_089_05 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, undated; HaleGE_04_00_089_06 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Observing cards, undated; HaleGE_04_00_089_07 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Spectrohelioscope and spectroheliograph correspondence, 1926–1936; HaleGE_04_00_090_01; 791 pages (Box 90, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 73, frames 20 to 812.
  - Spectrohelioscope mailing lists, undated; HaleGE_04_00_090_02; 17 pages (Box 90, Folder 2)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 73, frames 813 to 830.
- Biographical and Personal Papers, 1882–1940; 5; 9 linear feet (Tape HaleGE_02, Carton 2, Reel 74–80, Carton 4)
  Two boxes of correspondence concerning Hale's business affairs and eight boxes of bills and receipts have not been filmed or digitized.
  In the biographical and personal material are Hale's pocket diaries, an indispensable source for the study of any aspect of Hale's life.
  - Childhood notebooks, undated; HaleGE_05_00_091_01; 90 pages (Box 91, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 74, frames 20 to 109.
  - MIT notes, assignments and examination papers, 1890–1899; HaleGE_05_00_091_02; 165 pages (Box 91, Folder 2)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 74, frames 110 to 276.
  - Dinners, dance programs, graduation, 1890; HaleGE_05_00_091_03; 24 pages (Box 91, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 74, frames 277 to 301.
  - Student notebooks, 1882–1890; undated; HaleGE_05_00_091_04; 391 pages (Box 91, Folder 4)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 74, frames 302 to 694.
  - Autobiographical notes, 1933–1938; HaleGE_05_00_092_01; 270 pages (Box 92, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 75, frames 20 to 290.
  - Personal recollections notebook, 1935; HaleGE_05_00_092_02; 9 pages (Box 92, Folder 2)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 75, frames 291 to 300.
  - Bibliography, undated; HaleGE_05_00_092_03; 63 pages (Box 92, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 75, frames 301 to 365.
  - Poems and writings, undated; HaleGE_05_00_092_04; 12 pages (Box 92, Folder 4)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 75, frames 366 to 378.
  - Children's stories and poems, 1938; undated; HaleGE_05_00_092_05; 122 pages (Box 92, Folder 5)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 75, frames 379 to 501.
  - Passports, etc., 1916–1918; HaleGE_05_00_092_06; 59 pages (Box 92, Folder 6)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 75, frames 502 to 561.
  - Photographs, 1885–1888; undated; HaleGE_05_00_092_07; 25 pages (Box 92, Folder 7)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 75, frames 562 to 587.
  - Press clippings, HaleGE_05_00_092_08 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1886; HaleGE_05_00_093_01; 38 pages (Box 93, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 75, frames to.
  - Diary, 1890; HaleGE_05_00_093_02; 35 pages (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1893; HaleGE_05_00_093_03; 23 pages (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1894; HaleGE_05_00_093_04; 80 pages (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1901 (Box 175)
    This diary is accompanied by a transcript by Helen Holloway, prepared for W. L. W. Sargent. Both the original diary and the transcript were omitted from filming and digitization.
  - Diary, 1903; HaleGE_05_00_093_05; 42 pages (Box 93, Folder 5)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 76, frames to.
  - Diary, 1904; HaleGE_05_00_093_06; 39 pages (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1904; HaleGE_05_00_093_07; 80 pages (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1905; HaleGE_05_00_093_08; 7 pages (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1910; HaleGE_05_00_093_09; 53 pages (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1911; HaleGE_05_00_094_01; 72 pages (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1912; HaleGE_05_00_094_02; 56 pages (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1914; HaleGE_05_00_094_03; 50 pages (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1916; HaleGE_05_00_094_04; 91 pages (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1917; HaleGE_05_00_094_05; 85 pages (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1918; HaleGE_05_00_094_06; 55 pages (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1919; HaleGE_05_00_094_07; 59 pages (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1920; HaleGE_05_00_094_08; 45 pages (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1921; HaleGE_05_00_094_09; 69 pages (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1922; HaleGE_05_00_094_10; 74 pages (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Diary, 1922–1927; HaleGE_05_00_095_01; 55 pages (Box 95, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 77, frames to.
  - Diary, undated; HaleGE_05_00_095_02; 33 pages (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1924; HaleGE_05_00_095_03; 67 pages (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1925; HaleGE_05_00_095_04; 75 pages (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1926; HaleGE_05_00_095_05; 65 pages (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1927; HaleGE_05_00_095_06; 72 pages (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1929; HaleGE_05_00_095_07; 64 pages (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1928; HaleGE_05_00_095_08; 65 pages (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1930; HaleGE_05_00_095_09; 49 pages (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1931; HaleGE_05_00_095_10; 32 pages (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Diary, 1932; HaleGE_05_00_095_11; 60 pages (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Diary, 1933; HaleGE_05_00_096_01; 62 pages (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1934; HaleGE_05_00_096_02; 55 pages (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1935; HaleGE_05_00_096_03; 38 pages (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Diary, undated; HaleGE_05_00_096_04; 53 pages (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Diary, undated; HaleGE_05_00_096_05; 109 pages (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Diary, undated; HaleGE_05_00_096_06; 51 pages (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Requests and thanks, 1895–1937; HaleGE_05_00_097_01; 2505 pages (Box 97, Box 98, Box 99)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 78, frames 20 to 1467, and reel 79, frames 20 to 1078.
  - Honors, invitations, etc., 1893–1936; HaleGE_05_00_100_01; 265 pages (Box 100, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 80, frames 20 to 284.
  - Clubs, 1903–1928; HaleGE_05_00_100_02; 17 pages (Box 100, Folder 2)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 80, frames 285 to 302.
  - Personal effects, 1886; undated; HaleGE_05_00_100_03 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Books bought and sent, 1932; undated; HaleGE_05_00_101_01; 75 pages (Box 101, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 80, frames 393 to 468.
  - Book list, undated; HaleGE_05_00_101_02; 75 pages (Box 101, Folder 2)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 80, frames 469 to 544.
  - Books, memorials, articles, and miscellaneous letters, 1902–1938; HaleGE_05_00_101_03; 345 pages (Box 101, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 80, frames 545 to 890.
  - Condolence letters on death, 1938; HaleGE_05_00_102_01; 455 pages (Box 102, Folder 1)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 80, frames 891 to 1346.
  - Obituary notices, 1938; HaleGE_05_00_102_02 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Varied correspondence regarding George Ellery Hale memorial volume, 1939–1940; HaleGE_05_00_102_03; 55 pages (Box 102, Folder 3)
    This folder is represented in the microfilm edition of the Hale Papers by reel 80, frames 1347 to 1407.
  - Scrapbook of science clippings, 1892; HaleGE_05_00_102_04 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Business correspondence A–P, HaleGE_05_00_103_01 (Box 103)
  - Business correspondence R–Z, HaleGE_05_00_104_01 (Box 104)
  - Bills and receipts, unorganized, HaleGE_05_00_105_01 (Box 105, Box 106, Box 107, Box 108, Box 109, Box 110, Box 111, Box 112)
- Drafts of Articles, 1890–1932; 6; 6 linear feet
  None of the materials in this series have been filmed or digitized. The articles are available in published form without significant change from the drafts.
  - Photography of the Solar Prominences, 1890; HaleGE_06_00_113_01 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Drafts and notes for early papers, 1892; HaleGE_06_00_113_02 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Experiments with prominence photography with the horizontal telescope, HaleGE_06_00_113_03 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Early history of the spectroheliograph, HaleGE_06_00_113_04 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - The Spectroholiograph and Its Application, HaleGE_06_00_113_05 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Bands in the Spectra of Sun-Spots, HaleGE_06_00_113_06 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Report on the Bolomotric Work with Snow, HaleGE_06_00_113_07 (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Telescope, HaleGE_06_00_113_08 (Box 113, Folder 8)
  - Height of the Hydrogen Flocculi, HaleGE_06_00_113_09 (Box 113, Folder 9)
  - Five Foot Spectroheliograph of the Solar, HaleGE_06_00_113_10 (Box 113, Folder 10)
  - Observatory (Yerkes), HaleGE_06_00_113_11 (Box 113, Folder 11)
  - Reply to Recent Statements by M. Deslandres, HaleGE_06_00_113_12 (Box 113, Folder 12)
  - Five Foot Reflector of the Solar Observatory, HaleGE_06_00_113_13 (Box 113, Folder 13)
  - The Heliomicrometer, HaleGE_06_00_113_14 (Box 113, Folder 14)
  - The Tower Telescope, HaleGE_06_00_113_15 (Box 113, Folder 15)
  - The Measurement of Solar Photographs Made with the Spectroheliograph, HaleGE_06_00_113_16 (Box 113, Folder 16)
  - Solar Papers: Opportunities for Solar, HaleGE_06_00_113_17 (Box 113, Folder 17)
  - Research, Some New Possibilities for Solar Research, 1907; HaleGE_06_00_113_18 (Box 113, Folder 18)
  - On the Hydrogen Flocculi, HaleGE_06_00_113_19 (Box 113, Folder 19)
  - Whirls on Paper Prints, 1909; HaleGE_06_00_113_20 (Box 113, Folder 20)
  - Solar Voctices and Magnetic Fields, HaleGE_06_00_113_21 (Box 113, Folder 21)
  - Nature of the Flocculi, HaleGE_06_00_113_22 (Box 113, Folder 22)
  - The Spectroheliograph, HaleGE_06_00_113_23 (Box 113, Folder 23)
  - Preliminary Note on an Attempt to Detect the General Magnetic Field of the Sun, HaleGE_06_00_113_24 (Box 113, Folder 24)
  - Disk Eruptions and Magnetic Storms, 1915; HaleGE_06_00_113_25 (Box 113, Folder 25)
  - The Problem of Astrophysics, 1915; HaleGE_06_00_113_26 (Box 113, Folder 26)
  - The Minute Structure of the Solar Atmosphere, HaleGE_06_00_114_01 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Notes on a 25-Foot Reflector, 1922; HaleGE_06_00_114_02 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Mt. Wilson Photographic Bulletin #2, HaleGE_06_00_114_03 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - The Periodic Reversal of the Magnetic Polarity of Sun-Spots, HaleGE_06_00_114_04 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Visual Observations of the Solar Atmosphere, HaleGE_06_00_114_05 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - The Sun as a Research Laboratory, HaleGE_06_00_114_06 (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - Committee on the Study of the Physical Features of the Surface of the Moon, 1927–1928; HaleGE_06_00_114_07 (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - An Inexpensive Solar Telescope and Spectrohelioscope, 1928; HaleGE_06_00_114_08 (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - Solar Magnetism, 1928; HaleGE_06_00_114_09 (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Spectroheliographs and Spectrohelioscope, 1928; HaleGE_06_00_114_10 (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Work of the Solar Laboratory, 1908–1926; HaleGE_06_00_114_11 (Box 114, Folder 11)
  - Electromagnetic Theory of the Hydrogen Vortices above Sun-Spots, HaleGE_06_00_115_01 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - On the Nature of Sun-spots, HaleGE_06_00_115_02 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Polarities of Spots, HaleGE_06_00_115_03 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - The Direction of Whirl in Vortices above Sun-Spots, HaleGE_06_00_115_04 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Sun-spots, HaleGE_06_00_115_05 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Sun-spots, HaleGE_06_00_115_06 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Sun-spots, HaleGE_06_00_115_07 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks containing sun-spot data, HaleGE_06_00_115_08 (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Celestial Magnets, HaleGE_06_00_116_01 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Flocculi Papers, undated; HaleGE_06_00_116_02 (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Identification of Faint Lines in the Spectra of Sun-Spots, HaleGE_06_00_116_03 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Investigation of Sun-Spot Spectra, HaleGE_06_00_116_04 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Present Status of the Investigation of the Sun's General Magnetic Field, HaleGE_06_00_116_05 (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - Seeing, HaleGE_06_00_116_06 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - Simple Instruments for Photographing the Sun and Its Eruptions, HaleGE_06_00_116_07 (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - Some Vortex Experiments Bearing on the Nature of Sun-Spots, HaleGE_06_00_116_08 (Box 116, Folder 8)
  - Summary of Mt. Wilson Magnetic Observations of Sun-Spots, 1921; HaleGE_06_00_116_09 (Box 116, Folder 9)
  - The Direction of Rotation of Solar Storms, HaleGE_06_00_116_10 (Box 116, Folder 10)
  - The Fields of Force in the Atmosphere of the Sun, HaleGE_06_00_116_11 (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - Theories of the Aurora, HaleGE_06_00_116_12 (Box 116, Folder 12)
  - Some Uses of Spectroheliograph Plates, HaleGE_06_00_116_13 (Box 116, Folder 13)
  - Visual Observations of the Chromosphere and Prominences, HaleGE_06_00_116_14 (Box 116, Folder 14)
  - Calcium Furnace Spectra, HaleGE_06_00_117_01 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Matter in the Earth and Stars, HaleGE_06_00_117_02 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Microscopy, Descriptions and Drawings, Barometric Observations, HaleGE_06_00_117_03 (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Kenwood Observatory, HaleGE_06_00_117_04 (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, HaleGE_06_00_117_05 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous on moon, stars, and nebulae, HaleGE_06_00_117_06 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Instruments and Experiments: Spectroheliograph, HaleGE_06_00_117_07 (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Notes for a New Cosmic Laboratory: Signals from the Sun, HaleGE_06_00_117_08 (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Notes on Observations, 1926–1930; HaleGE_06_00_117_09 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Report: Solar Observations, HaleGE_06_00_117_10 (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Solar Rotation, HaleGE_06_00_117_11 (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Solar Spectrum Chart, HaleGE_06_00_117_12 (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Solar Spectra and Photographs, HaleGE_06_00_117_13 (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - Sunspots and Radio Distrubances: Data, HaleGE_06_00_117_14 (Box 117, Folder 14)
  - The Life History of a Star, HaleGE_06_00_117_15 (Box 117, Folder 15)
  - Polarity Volume Working Copy, HaleGE_06_00_118_01 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Sun and Solar Spectra, HaleGE_06_00_118_02 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Polar notes: other miscellaneous material, HaleGE_06_00_118_03 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Introduction Polarity Volume (unused), HaleGE_06_00_118_04 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Mt. Wilson Photographic Map of the Sun-spot, HaleGE_06_00_118_05 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Spectrum notes, HaleGE_06_00_118_06 (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Unpublished tabulations, HaleGE_06_00_118_07 (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous measures, HaleGE_06_00_118_08 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Solar Laboratory miscellaneous, HaleGE_06_00_118_09 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes, HaleGE_06_00_118_10 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous articles and manuscripts, Letters on the Sun, HaleGE_06_00_118_11 (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - Infusoria, Branchiopoda, Rotifera, Foramenifera, Rhizopoda, Diatomacea, Porifera, Protozoa, and Desmidieae, HaleGE_06_00_119_01 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Notes on the Origin of the Yerkes Observator, HaleGE_06_00_119_02 (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Building a New Observatory, HaleGE_06_00_119_03 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Some Observatory Problems, HaleGE_06_00_119_04 (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Some Opportunities for Astronomical Work with Inexpensive Equipment, HaleGE_06_00_119_05 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Work for the Amateur Astronomer, HaleGE_06_00_119_06 (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Responsibilities of the Scientist, HaleGE_06_00_119_07 (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - International Cooperation in Research, HaleGE_06_00_119_08 (Box 119, Folder 8)